PERSONAL DETAILS

ZAC HOBDAY 07896834742 zachobday0@gmail.com

PROFILE

Technology has been a staple throughout my childhood from Playstation1 to Gameboy and Mario, I have grown up with technology integrated into my everyday life and my growing passion for it has driven me into my chosen field of Computer Science. After doing well in Information technology at GCSE I chose to continue into A level by studying BTEC IT and I am so glad I did, my mind has been opened up to so many new possibilities within the area and really sparks my hunger to learn. It was only a year ago when I discovered I have a true talent for programming, I created a simple card game app for an android device. I love the methodical nature of programming and the endless possibilities inspire me to solve all kinds of different problems. I also have a keen eye for design; I studied a diploma in computer based digital media where I discovered my artistic flair. Within this course I learnt how to use Adobe Photoshop, I enjoy the logic behind a good composition, understanding how certain colours can draw your eye towards elements and how the eye naturally reads across a page is fascinating. Recently I was selected and commissioned to construct a website for a large local gritting business, I drew upon my knowledge from digital media as well as the skills laid down by computing to help me in my creative practise. I redesigned their image bringing them up to date with modern trends and expectations and used WordPress to programme and integrate their website).

After my college degree I pursued an apprenticeship in software development instead of going to University as I felt it was the best move for me to learn in a work environment, also I had heard from other apprentices that they had enjoyed there course and were know working in full time development roles. I did my apprenticeship with MrSite where I worked primarily on their website building software called Omnibuilder which was an Angular application where I worked on the backend APIs and services as well as some MVC applications built around the application. I enjoyed my time at MrSite but felt it was time to move on to different challenges.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Imberhorne School (2011-2012)

GCSE: Additional Science AA Geography B **English Literature B** English Language B Maths C Food Tech C

History (Short Course) C

Hayward Heath College (2012-2015)

Btec Subsidiary Diploma in IT Merit ABC Digital Arts Diploma Pass

Level 3 Software and Development Apprenticeship

MTA in Software Development Fundamentals

City & Guilds Level 3 Certificate in IT Systems and Principles

City & Guilds Level 3 Diploma in IT Professional Competence

WORK EXPERIENCE

(2012-2015) Homebase Sales Assistant

(February 2015 – March 2016) MrSite – Junior Software Developer (Apprentice)

- Working on the backend code base in C# working on the API Endpoints and the data modelling processes.
- Fixing Bugs whether this would be for a release to the system or on a case by case basis from support tickets.
- Working on the company website when changes are needed like offers and deals.
- Testing and verifying new functionality.
- Writing unit tests around code blocks.
- Working with SQL including Work with Entity Framework as well as using scripts and managing the databases with SQL Manager
- Working with a NoSql Database (MongoDB)
- My frontend work has mainly come around MVC applications which has developed me functional skills in HTML and CSS.
- Working in the Front End of a large SPA using AngularJS

(April 2016 - Present) Justis Publishing - Junior Developer

- Working on large backend API System in C# as well as a model system for the Raven Database
- Working with the RavenDB a no SQL database used to store millions of documents for the product.
- Working in the Front End of another SPA using TypeScript, Backbone/Marrionette and Aurellia.

IT SKILLS

Whilst at my college course I did quite a bit of programming including languages like C# and Visual Basic and I have done work on databases and Web Design using Dreamweaver. Outside of my course I have worked on small companies websites using WordPress and .NET

During my apprenticeship at work and in the training facilities I have focused my work on C# and the .NET framework. I have mostly been involved in building new and developing api's for the site builders front end but also worked on repository's and services for these api's to call as well.

I have also been involved in front end work whilst in both my junior roles and i am familiar with languages such as JQuery, Backbone, Bootstrap. I have also worked on more advanced JavaScript languages such as Typescript, Angular JS and Aurelia.

During my time at MrSite as well I also worked a lot on MVC applications which has helped me develop my HTML and CSS skills as well.

I have also done a lot of data analyses work as well and I am capable of working with SQL databases as well as mongoDB.

I am interested in the MEAN Stack of modern web development and have enjoyed reading books on the topic and building dummy applications using the frameworks. I think I was drawn into this method having previously worked with AngularJS

and MongoDB, so I was familiar with those frameworks and the idea of creating a full web app built predominantly in one language, JavaScript, drew me in further.

I have created websites for personal clients and friends examples which can be seen on my website, I enjoy creating these sites in my free time and is a good way to try out new ideas and become exposed to new problems outside of the office.

Programmes I am familiar with in terms of the development life cycle are Octopus Deploy and TeamCity.

I am also used to developing in an agile environment where we have planned sprints every 2 weeks and had a retrospective at the end.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

<u>Ian Horton Contractual Developer 07779322535</u>

Worked with me in my first development role.

Anton Scipio Infrastructure Manager 07834241966

Was my apprenticeship manager during my time at MrSite.

Please check out my personal website for more information at www.zachobday.com

Celticwt.co.uk (website I made for a client)